Guide to the Jeffery Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials, 1939-1998, bulk 1974-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jeffery Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials 1939-1998, bulk 1974-1998
Jeffery, Robert K.
Extent: about 459 items 4.5 linear feet
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
jefferydiamond
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jeffery Collection of Diamond Promotional Materials was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2000.
Biographical Note
Jeffery is a longtime administrator and lecturer in retail sales, administration, and the manufacturing of jewelry.
Collection Overview
Collection documents the artwork and printed promotional materials Robert K. Jeffery commissioned, used, or referenced in diamond advertising. Most items are the output of the advertising agency N. W. Ayer and Son, Inc., often featuring De Beers diamonds and outdoor advertising promotions. Other items are more general to the diamond marketing industry, including marketing statistics, and gemology periodicals. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Jeffery, Robert K.; N.W. Ayer and Son; De Beers Consolidated Mines; Advertising -- History; Advertising, Outdoor; Diamonds.; Precious stones; Jewelry -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Jewelry trade; Market surveys; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Accession #2000-0328
  - Printed Materials (Box 1)
    - DeBeers Diamond Promotion Guide
    - DeBeers commissioned art
    - DeBeers Annual Reports, 1983-1987
    - 50 Years of DeBeers Ads
    - DeBeers Ads - foreign (slides)
    - DeBeers Carat Club
    - DeBeers Promotional Materials
    - Ayer Glossary of Advertising and Related Terms, 1977
    - Ayer: Information for employees
    - Gems and Gemology, 1990-1998
    - Marketing workshop binder
    - The Market for Diamond Jewelry, United States, 1982
    - Diamond Promotion Guide
    - Article on advertising from National Jeweler, 1986 June 1
    - 1988 Red Book, The Market for Diamond Jewelry, United States
    - 1988 Blue Book, The Market for Diamond Jewelry, United States
    - Misc. diamond promotional materials
    - Robert K. Jeffery Resumé
  - Videotapes (VHS) (Box 2)
    The videotapes are closed for 15 years from date of creation.
    - Rock video, An International Affair, 2 spots
    - Training program: The Diamond Engagement Ring
    - Training programs with booklet
      - Diamonds for Men, 1987
      - Diamond Product Knowledge, 1988
    - NW Ayer, Field Force Conference Tape
    - Ayer Field Force Conference Tape Revised, 1990, (2 tapes)
    - Diamond Rules
    - From Rules to Riches
    - Power of Love, 1990
    - DPS Videos, (2 tapes)
    - Large Stone Ring, 1988
    - Diamond Masters Speeches
    - NW Ayer, Spring '89
    - Ayer 1990 Dealer Version, Commercial Reel
    - Adamas K - The Wizard of Opportunity
    - Beauty of Diamonds, videotape (Beta)
  - Promotional Materials (matches, playing cards)
  - Album of DeBeers advertisments, 1939-1990s (Box 3)
  - Printed artwork and diamond promotional posters (Opaperfolder 1)